Guide to the Mid-Hudson Valley Transgender Association records, 1970-2014.
Mid-Hudson Valley Transgender Association records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Mid-Hudson Valley Transgender Association records, 1970-2014.
7832
Brown, Jan,
2.6 cubic feet.
Publications, printed materials, photographs, video recordings.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Programs, photographs, books, serials, papers, conference materials, and videos documenting the Club's activities and recent literature on transgender themes, including intersexuality. Books and serials from their library are cataloged individually.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
The Mid-Hudson Valley Transgender Association (MHVTA) is a support group for transgender people in the Hudson Valley region of New York State and New Jersey. Meetings have been held in Poughkeepsie, New York and other cities.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Programs, photographs, books, serials, papers, conference materials, and videos documenting the Club's activities and recent literature on transgender themes, including intersexuality. Books and serials from their library are cataloged individually.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Brown, Jan,; Mid-Hudson Valley Transgender Association (N.Y. and N.J.)
Subjects:
Hudson River Valley (N.Y. and N.J.); Intersex people -- New York (State) -- Poughkeepsie -- Social conditions.; Intersex people -- New Jersey -- Social conditions.; Transgender people -- New York (State) -- Poughkeepsie -- Social conditions.; Transgender people -- New Jersey -- Social conditions.; Transgender people in motion pictures.; Transgender children.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Folder 27 from Box 2 and Folders 3, 59 from Box 3 are restricted until January 2041.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Organization Materials
Box 3
a. Mid-Hudson Valley Transgender Association
b. Other Organizations
Series II. Event & Conference Related Materials
Box 3
a. Brochures
b. Programs
c. Presentations
d. Newsletters
e. Invitations
f. Trip Reports
g. Other
Series III. Transgender Lifestyle
Box 2
Series IV. Publications
Boxes 2-4
a. Papers
b. Guides / Resources
c. Articles
d. Advocacy & Legal Materials
e. Reports
f. Self-Published Books
g. Magazines / Catalogues
h. Erotic Magazines
Series V. Email Correspondence
Box 3
Series VI. Media
Boxes 1-2
a. Videos
b. DVDs
c. CDs
Series VII. Miscellaneous
Box 2
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Organization Materials
  Arranged chronologically within each subseries.
  - Mid-Hudson Valley Transgender Association
    - Flyers, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - List of Members and Others, 2002-04-19 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Contents transferred to Accession File until restriction is lifted.
      Access restrictions apply.
    - Mid-Hudson Valley Transgender Association Correspondence, 2002-03 - 2003-12 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Call to Action and Trans-Action, 2002-04 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Other Organizations
    - Imperial Court of New York Brochure, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Imperial Court of New York; New York, New York
    - Tiffany Club of New England Brochure, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
      Waltham, Massachusetts
    - Society for the Second Self (Tri-Ess), 1991 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Renaissance Background Papers, 1994-09 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      Printed March 1999
      Wayne, Pennsylvania
    - Vida Nueva Sponsorship Form, 1997-03 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Mid-Hudson Kairos Ministry Newsletter, 1998-03 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      Vol. 1 No. 2
      Walden, New York
    - Renaissance Manual for Chapters/Affiliates, 1998-07 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      Renaissance Transgender Association, Inc.; Wayne, Pennsylvania
    - Vida Nueva Candidate Reference Form, 1998-11 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      Mid-Hudson Vida Nueva; Staatsburg, New York
    - Society for the Second Self (Tri-Ess): Kappa Beta, 1999-09 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      Includes The Pink Slip Newsletter Vol. XI No. 1
      Tri-Ess Kappa Beta Chapter; Charlotte, North Carolina
    - Mid-Hudson Tres Dias, 1999-12-23 - 2000-04-12 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      Staatsburg, New York
    - South Florida Gender Coalition, 2001-09-20 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      Florida
    - Renaissance Chapter Plan Draft, 2002-02-09 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - The Transgenderist, 2002-08 - 2002-09 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      Vol. MMII No. 3
      Transgender Independence Club; Albany, New York
    - Society for the Second Self (Tri-Ess):Rho Eta Chi, 2002-08-26 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      Phoenix, Arizona
    - CrossPort, 2002-08-26 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - North Alabama Gender Center, 2002-08-26 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      North Alabama Gender Center; North Alabama
    - Illusions - Police! So what's the story?, 2002-08-29 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      Illusions Transgender Social Club of Alberta
    - Delaware Renaissance Newsletter, 2004-02 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      Vol. 11 No, 2
      Wilmington, Delaware
    - Transgender Library Materials, 2006-04 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence on Tiffany Club of New England, 2007-02-10 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Series II. Event & Conference Related Materials
  Arranged by type of material and then chronologically within those subseries.
  - Brochures
    - Mid-Hudson Vida Nueva Weekend, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 21)
      Newburgh, New York
    - The International Foundation for Gender Education Annual Conference Brochure, 2008-03-31 - 2008-04-05 (Box 3, Folder 22)
      Tucson, Arizona
    - Fantasia Fair Brochure, 2008-10-19 - 2009-10-25 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      Provincetown, Massachusetts
    - Bard Summerscape 2014, 2014-07-03 - 2014-08-16 (Box 3, Folder 24)
      Annandale-on-Hudson, New York
  - Programs
    - Southern Comfort Film, undated; Davis, Kate (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - The California Cuties Souvenir Program, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 26)
      Lakewood, California
    - First Event Programs, 2003-01 - 2010 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      Tiffany Club of New England; Woburn, Massachusetts
    - Fantasia Fair Participant's Guide, 2007-10-14 - 2010-10-24 (Box 3, Folder 28)
      No. 33-36
    - Special First Event Issue, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 29)
      Vol. 22 No. 1
      Rosebuds - Tiffany Club of New England; Waltham, Massachusetts
    - Southern Comfort Conference Guide, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 30)
      Atlanta, Georgia
    - Transgender 2009: The Liberty Conference Program, 2009-04-29 - 2009-05-02 (Box 3, Folder 31)
      Philadelphia, Pennsylvania
    - Be-All Conference Program, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 32)
      Chicago, Illinois
    - Fantasia Fair Participant's Guide, 2011-10-16 - 2014-10-21 (Box 3, Folder 33)
      No. 37 (2 copies), 39-40
    - Transgender Lives: The Intersection of Health and Law Conference, 2014-04-26 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      Connecticut TransAdvocacy Coalition; Farmington, Connecticut
    - Playbills, 2014-04-23 - 2015-01-03 (Box 3, Folder 35)
      Includes playbills for Casa Valentina and Lypsinka! The Trilogy, and Casa Valentina tickets
  - Presentations
    - Observations About Transgender People, 1990-08-11; Fraser, Lin (Box 3, Folder 36)
      Presented to ETVC San Francisco
      San Francisco, California
    - Myth, Stereotype, and Cross-Gender Identity in the DSM-IV, 1996; Wilson, Katherine K.; Hammond, Barbara E. (Box 3, Folder 37)
      Presented at the Association for Women in Psychology 21st Annual Women in Psychology Conference
      Portland, Oregon
    - Who We Are: A Survey of Crossdressers, 1999; Sullivan, Yvonne (Box 3, Folder 38)
      3 copies
    - The Roots of Crossdressing and Transsexualism: Nature and Nurture Revisited, 2007; Schott, Richard L. (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Transgender Health: Reconceptualizing Pathology as Wellness, 2007-04-07; Park, Pauline (Box 3, Folder 40)
      2 copies
    - Communication & Body Awareness: An Introduction to Gender & Movement, 2010; Whitehouse, Lezli A. (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Transtheology 101, 2011-10; Beattie, JamieGhee, Rev. (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Being Trans, Aging and Being An Elder, 2014-04-26; Stone, Moonhawk River, Rev. (Box 3, Folder 43)
      Presented at the 8th Annual Transgender Lives Conference
      Farmington, Connecticut
  - Newsletters
    - Rosebuds, 2003-01 (Box 3, Folder 44)
      Tiffany Club of New England; Waltham, Massachusetts
    - TransEventsUSA Newsletter, 2006 - 2007 (Box 3, Folder 45)
      TransEventsUSA, Inc.
  - Invitations
    - Kutsher's Country Club Event Information, 1999 - 2000 (Box 3, Folder 46)
      Monticello, New York
    - Access Awards Invitation, 2009-06-10 (Box 3, Folder 47)
      Albany, New York
  - Trip Reports
    - International Foundation for Gender Education Convention Trip Report, 2006-04-05 - 2007-04-15; Brown, Jan (Box 3, Folder 48)
      Mid-Hudson Valley Transgender Association; Philadelphia, Pennsylvania
    - Fantasia Fair Trip Reports, 2007 - 2010; Brown, Jan (Box 3, Folder 49)
      Mid-Hudson Valley Transgender Association; Provincetown, Massachusetts
    - Southern Comfort Conference Trip Report, 2009-09; Brown, Jan (Box 3, Folder 50)
      Mid-Hudson Valley Transgender Association; Atlanta, Georgia
  - Other
    - Fantasia Fair Business Card Template, undated; Brown, Jan (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Fantasia Fair Sale Advertisement, undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Southern Comfort Conference Pen, undated; MU-1705 (Box 3)
    - NYTG Conference Notes, 2002-04 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Media Collison: New Visions Catalogue, 2004-05-04 - 2004-05-06 (Box 3, Folder 53)
      Mahwah, New Jersey
    - International Foundation for Gender Education Conference, 2007-04-10 - 2007-04-14 (Box 3, Folder 54)
      Includes schedule, photos
    - Pride March News Printout, 2009-05 (Box 3, Folder 55)
      New Paltz, New York
    - Big Gay Hudson Valley Pride Preview Party, 2009-05 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Sissy Maid Competition Correspondence, 2009-05 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Tales of Rebellion: The Stonewall Riots 40 Years Later Flyer, 2009-06-25 (Box 3, Folder 58)
      New York, New York
    - Fantasia Fair Presenter List, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Fantasia Fair Contact List Correspondence, 2010-04 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Fantasia Fair Advertising Agreemen, 2013-10-20 - 2013-10-27 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Fantasia Fair Oral History, 2014 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Redefining Realness Notes, 2014 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Provincetown Lease Confirmation, 2014-11 (Box 3, Folder 64)
- Series III. Transgender Lifestyle
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Wig Care Instructions, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Enhancement Undergarments, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Classic Curves International; Wilmington, California
  - Medication Catalog, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Lady Ellen's Deportment Advice, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Beauty & Makeup Tips, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Queen Cushion Shoes Flyer, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Buffalo, New York
  - Hudson Valley Electrolysis Materials, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Poughkeepsie, New York
  - Trans-friendly Nightclubs & Taverns, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - The Motives Custom Face, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Business Cards, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - List of Transgender Television Episodes, 1991 - 1992 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Carousel Aviation, 1993-11 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Includes catalogs, price sheets, order forms
    Carousel Aviation; Red Bluff, California
  - Secrets to an Awesome Makeover, 1998; Isato, Kalina (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Unbound printout; edition 1.6 printed July 2001
    TransVamp Publications, Ltd.
  - Strength Exercises, 1998-01 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Windsor Jewelry Catalogue, 2000 - 2009 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    AmeriMark; Cleveland, Ohio
  - The Big & The Bold Can Look Beautiful Too!, 2001-07 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Transgender Community News
  - Rosebuds - Tiffany Club Newsletter Excerpt, 2006-11 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Transgender Voice, 2006-09 - 2009-09 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    The College of Saint Rose Department of Communication Science and Disorders; Capital Region Ear, Nose & Throat; TG Forum; Albany, New York
  - Gender Transition Plan, 2008-08 - 2008-09 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    Port Ewen, New York
  - Paula Young Catalogue, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    Brockton, Massachusetts
  - Call for Submissions Flyer, 2014-12; Patton, Jude (Box 2, Folder 29)
    Asks for stories of "LGBTIQQ People and their emotional bonds with Companion Animals"
- Series IV. Publications
  Arranged by type of material and then chronologically within those groups.
  - Papers
    - Sexual Orientation Confusion Among Spouses of Transvestites and Transsexual Following Disclosure of Spouse's Gender Dysphoria, undated; Hunt, Sallie; Main, Terri L. (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Patterns of Marital Adjustment, 1988; Docter, Richard F. (Box 3, Folder 66)
      Printed August 30, 2000
      Plenum Press; New York
    - The Psychology of Cross-dressing, 1992; Hayman, Suzie; Cowan, Vic (Box 3, Folder 67)
      Vol. 25 No. 10; printed June 2000
      Forum
    - Men in Dresses, 1995; Coleman, Vernon (Box 3, Folder 68)
      Printed October 2, 2001
      European Medical Journal; United Kingdom
    - The Transgendered Philosopher, 2001; Gilbert, Michael 'Miqqi Alicia' (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - GenderPAC, The Transgender Rights Movement and the Perils of a Post-Identity Politics Paradigm, 2003; Park, Pauline (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - The Gender Variant Phenomenon: A Developmental Review, 2003-01-27; Vitale, Anne (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Guides / Resources
    - Decision Management Associates, Inc., undated; Berlin, Sarah E. (Box 3, Folder 72)
      Macon, Georgia
    - Transgender Resource Cards, undated (Box 3, Folder 73)
      Massachusetts Transgender Political Coalition; Massachusetts
    - LGBTQ Brochures, undated (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Transgender Support Group Resources, 1992 - 2002 (Box 3, Folder 75)
      Printed February 28, 2007
    - The Transgender Guide Q & A, 1998; Glass, Krystle (Box 3, Folder 76)
      Printed December 24, 2002
      TG Guide
    - A Few Words About Internet Security and Safety, 1999-01-21 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Gayle's Transgender Resources, 2000; Shetland, Gayle Elizabeth (Box 3, Folder 78)
      Printed November 27, 2002
    - Coming Out Narratives, 2000-05-30 - 2003-04-16 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Cross Dressin & Deuteronomy 22.5, 2000-07-31; Tilsen, Rabbi (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - The Real Truth About Crossdressing, 2000-08-30; Sherman, Ellen (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Sexploration Q & A, 2000-08-30; Kornreich, Jennifer; Granzig, William (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Transvestite and Crossdresser Issues FAQ, 2001-06-03; Lewis, Amy A.; Richards, Kymberleigh; Wilson, Diane (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - Human Right's Office Transgender/Transsexual Resources, 2001-10-08 (Box 3, Folder 84)
      Website printouts
      Queen's University; Ontario, Canada
    - Trans Inclusion Policy Manual for Women's Organizations, 2002-01 - 2002-02; Darke, Julie; Cope, Allison (Box 3, Folder 85)
      Women/Trans Dialogue Planning Committee; Trans Alliance Society
    - transACTION: A Transgender Curriculum for Churches and Religious Institutions, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 86)
      National Gay and Lesbian Task Force: Institute for Welcoming Resources
    - Beyond the Weekend, 2006; Sakura, Minako (Box 3, Folder 87)
      Printout of eBook
      The TrannyWeb Digital Press
    - New York Local Resources, 2006-02-13 (Box 3, Folder 88)
      OutProud; Queer America; New York
    - STD & HIV Facts, 2007 - 2008-03 (Box 3, Folder 89)
      New York Department of Health; Albany, New York
    - Trans Abuse Handouts, 2007-09 (Box 3, Folder 90)
      For Ourselves: Reworking Gender Expression (FORGE); Milwaukee, Wisconsin
    - Welcoming Our Trans Family and Friends, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 91)
      PFLAG; Washington, D.C.
    - True Colors, Inc. Sexual Minority Youth and Family Services Resource Guide, 2008 - 2009 (Box 3, Folder 92)
      Manchester, Connecticut
    - Kids of Trans Resource Guide, 2008-03 - 2008-05; Canfield-Lenfest, Monica (Box 3, Folder 93)
      COLAGE; San Francisco, California
    - When the Opposite Sex Isn't Materials, 2008-10; Samons, Sandra L. (Box 3, Folder 94)
    - Explaining Crossdressing to the Public, 2009; Lynn, Teri (Box 3, Folder 95)
    - Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual and Transgender Directory of Services and Resources, 2011-06 (Box 3, Folder 96)
      New York City Comptroller; New York, New York
    - Transgender Parent Picture Books List, 2013 (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - The Gender Book Photocopy, 2014; Bostian, Boston; Reiff Hill, Mel; Mays, Jay (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Articles
    - Playboy Interview with Wendy/Walter Carlos, 1979-05 (Box 3, Folder 99)
    - Transgender Article Printouts, 1995 - 2006-02-10 (Box 3, Folder 100)
    - LGBTQ Book Reviews, 2000-05 - 2005-04 (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - LGBTQ News Article Printouts, 2002-01-10 - 2002-11-18 (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - Gender Advocacy Internet News (GAIN) Digest, 2002-04-19; Morgan, Gwyneth Rhian (Box 3, Folder 103)
    - LGBTQ Newspaper Clippings, 2002-10-29 - 2014-09-27 (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - Advocacy & Legal Materials
    - International Bill of Gender Rights, 1996-07-04 (Box 3, Folder 105)
      International Conference on Transgender Law and Employment Policy Inc.; Cooperstown, New York
    - Guidelines Regarding Gender Identity Discrimination, 2002-04 (Box 3, Folder 106)
    - New York Association for Gender Rights Advocacy, 2002 - 2005-05 (Box 3, Folder 107)
      Includes newsletter Vol. 1 No.3, Pauline Park testimony on proposed amendment to Article 207 of the New York City Health Code
      New York Association for Gender Rights Advocacy
    - New York Transgender Rights Coalition, 2014 (Box 3, Folder 108)
  - Reports
    - A Report of the National Transgender Discrimination Survey, undated (Box 3, Folder 109)
      National Gay and Lesbian Task Force; National Center for Transgender Equality
    - Preliminary TVTP Transgender Violence Report for Transgender Awareness 2014, 2014 (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - Self-Published Books
    - A Thank You Book, 2010; Gilbert, Miqqi Alicia (Box 3)
    - Miqqi Alicia's Thanks, 2013; Gilbert, Miqqi Alicia (Box 3)
  - Magazines / Catalogues
    - Crossdresser Videos, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
      MAGS INC; Sherman Oaks, California
    - En Femme, 1989-08; Buchanan, Rebecca J. (Box 2, Folder 2)
      No. 13
      Trenton, New Jersey
    - Blue Moon Catalogue, 1993-03 - 1993-05 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Canada
    - New York Magazine, 1997-03-03 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      Vol. 30 No. 8
    - Female Mimics International, 1999-06-10 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Utterly Fabulous Printouts, 2002 - 2003 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      No.1-2
      The WayOut Publishing Co Ltd
    - LGBTQ Magazines, 2005-07 - 2014-08 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      Includes InsideOut Hudson Valley, Pride, Wedding Pride, NYC Pride Guide, Metrosource
      New York
    - GO, 2014-04 - 2014-05 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      Vol. 13 No. 1
  - Erotic Magazines
    - Mistress Vixen's Panty Boys, undated; Mistress Vixen (Box 4)
      Vol. 1 No. 6
      Babylon, New York
    - New TV, The, undated (Box 4)
    - TV Forum, undated (Box 4)
      Vol. 2 No. 2
    - Transvestite Key Club, 1990-11 (Box 4)
      Vol. 2 No. 3
    - Transvestites on Parade, 1990-11 (Box 4)
    - Shemale Sex Techniques, 1993-03 (Box 4)
    - Shemalea, 1995-07 (Box 4)
    - Silk, Satin and Lace, 1995-07; Avery, Carol (Box 4)
      Vol. 2 No. 1
    - TV Happenings, 1995-07 (Box 4)
      Vol. 3 No. 1
    - Feminique, 1995 - 1999 (Box 4)
    - Shemales Out for the Day, 1997 (Box 4)
      Ontario, Canada
    - Kim Christy's Sissy Expose, 1998-09 (Box 4)
      Vol. 6 No. 6 Is. 42
      Sun Valley, California
- Series V. Email Correspondence
  - Inspirational Email Correspondence, 1999-08 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Driving Directions Correspondence, 2000 - 2009 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Dr. Laura on Cross-Dressing Correspondence, 2000-01 - 2000-06 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Ellen Sherman Documentary Correspondence, 2000-07 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Melissa Coming Out Narrative Correspondence, 2000-08 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Carrie Davis Testimony Correspondence, 2002-04 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Series VI. Media
  Arranged within each subseries by assigned item number.
  - Videos
    - All Dressed Up, undated; V-9249 (Box 1)
    - Untitled, undated; V-9257 (Box 1)
    - Untitled, undated; V-9258 (Box 1)
    - Untitled, undated; V-9259 (Box 1)
    - Untitled, undated; V-9260 (Box 1)
    - Soldier's Story, undated; V-9262 (Box 1)
    - She-male Encounters Collection 5, 1980; V-9265 (Box 1)
      Caballero Productions
    - Where the Girls are Boys!, 1991; V-9247 (Box 1)
    - Dateline: "A Man & A Woman", 1992 - 2014; V-9227 (Box 1)
      NBC
    - Brush Up on Beauty, 1993; V-9264 (Box 1)
      Mary Kay Inc.
    - Just Like a Woman, 1994-07-22; V-9261 (Box 1)
      Rank Organisation; Zenith Entertainment
    - Confident About Color, 1996; V-9263 (Box 1)
    - Different for Girls, 1997-09-12; V-9248 (Box 1)
      BBC Films
    - Investigative Reports: "Transgender Revolution", 1998; V-9230 (Box 1)
      A&E Television Networks
    - TS/TV 2000-2002, 2000-01-24 - 2002-05-07; V-9254 (Box 1)
      Includes written list of video contents
    - Boy or Girl?; Science of the Sexes, 2001-01-12; V-9246 (Box 1)
      Discovery Channel
    - MSNBC Investigates: "The Secret Wardrobe", 2001-02-24; V-9228-9229 (Box 1)
      MSNBC
    - 2002, 2003 TS & TG's, 2002-05-23 - 2003-05-06; V-9255 (Box 1)
    - Normal, 2003-01-21; V-9238-9240 (Box 1)
      HBO
    - "Sex Change"; "Role Reversal", 2003-03; V-9232-9233 (Box 1)
      TLC; A&E Television Networks
    - "Role Reversal", 2003-03; V-9234 (Box 1)
    - Oprah - May 6-7, 2003, 2003-05; V-9236-9237 (Box 1)
      Harpo Productions
    - 2003-2006 TV's/TS's, 2003-10-03 - 2006-08-01; V-9256 (Box 1)
    - In the Life: "Mergers and Acquisitions"; Sex Change; Switching Sexes: The Aftermath, 2004-09 - 2008-01; V-9242 (Box 1)
      In The Life Media; Discovery Health
    - In the Life: "Mergers and Acquisitions", 2004-09; V-9243 (Box 1)
      In The Life Media
    - Oprah: "State of the Union", 2005; V-9235 (Box 1)
    - The Dr. Keith Ablow Show: Helen & Betty; The Tyra Show: “We’re 7 & 8 Years Old and Know We Are Transgender”; Unusual Family; 2005 NYC Gay Pride Parade; Wisecrack, 2005 - 2010; V-9241 (Box 1)
    - A Girl Like Me: The Gwen Araujo Story, 2006-06-19; V-9244 (Box 1)
      Braun Entertainment Group; Lifetime Television
    - A Girl Like Me: The Gwen Araujo Story; 20/20: "My Secret Self", 2006-06-19 - 2007-04-27; V-9245 (Box 1)
      Lifetime Television; ABC News
    - The Secret Lives of Women: "Women Married to Crossdressers", 20006-08-15; V-9250-9251 (Box 1)
      WE: Women's Entertainment
    - 30 Days: "New Age", 2006-08-16; V-9253 (Box 1)
      FX Networks, LLC
    - 20/20: "My Secret Self"; The Tyra Show: “We’re 7 & 8 Years Old and Know We Are Transgender”; Insider & Entertainment Tonight, 2007-04-27 - 2010; V-9231 (Box 1)
      ABC News
    - Trinidad, 2008-06-22; V-9252 (Box 1)
      Surly Puppy
  - DVDs
    - Building Alliances and Community, 2005-11-12; DVD-1889; Boyd, Helen (Box 2)
    - The Secret Lives of Women: "Women Married to Crossdressers", 2006-08-15; DVD-1890-1891 (Box 2)
    - Rendezvous at Renaissance, undated; DVD-1892-1899
      8 copies
    - Carol & Company Reunion 1990, 1990; DVD-1900
    - In Memory of Rita, 2001; DVD-1901 (Box 2)
      Gender Education & Media; Yellow Panther Production
    - The Phil Donahue Show: "Tula", 1991 - 1992; DVD-1902
    - How-to Guide: Quick Start to Bare Beauty, 2007; DVD-1903 (Box 2)
      Bare Escentuals
    - Feminine Movement: A Private Consultation on Feminine Pose, 2003; DVD-1904 (Box 2)
      FemImage
    - A Girl Like Me: The Gwen Araujo Story, 2006-06-19; DVD-1905-1906
      Braun Entertainment Group
    - Different for Girls, 1997-09-12; DVD-1907 (Box 2)
    - Breakfast on Pluto, 2006-01-06; DVD-1908 (Box 2)
      Pathé Pictures International
    - Drag How To, 2002; DVD-1909 (Box 2)
      Vol. 1-2
      Bizarre Video Productions